

Andreas Klein
Agile Coach & Scrum Master

COLOGNE AREA, GERMANY / +49 173 8888 987 / ANDY@IXIS.IO / WWW.IXIS.IO

Figuring out how to get things done in larger Teams as a <u>certified</u>

<u>Scrum Master</u>, not just in the software Industry. I help Agencies and
Companies to realize Products with Value and with a Focus on
happy People. I also enable <u>Conferences</u> to share Experiences.

Outside of the web, I'm a proud father of two beautiful children, a passionate freestyle skateboarder/snowboarder and I like the taste of good espresso.

If there is still time, I write on my personal blog http://ixis.io about things of the Internet.

My other Profiles on the web:



twitter.com/ixisio



github.com/ixisio



xing.com/andreas_klein156

Skills

- · Certified Scrum Master
- Agile Coaching
- Scaling Scrum with multiple Teams
- Change Management for Agile Software Development Teams
- Frontend Development and Consulting
- Workshops, Trainings and Coaching
- Product Ownership
- Kanban
- Continuous Improvement

Project Experience

Vaillant Group // Connected Devices - IoT, Websites

- Customer: Vaillant Group Business Services GmbH
- Role: Agile Coaching, Scrum Master
- Date: Jan 2017 present

http://www.vaillant-group.com

Toom Baumarkt // Websites & Shops

- Customer: Rewe Group, Fork GmbH
- Role: Agile Coaching, Frontend Architect
- Date: Apr 2016 December 2016
- Technologies: Scrum, ES6, React.js

https://www.toom.de/

Aktion Mensch // Accessibility Workshop, Training

• Customer: Aktion Mensch e.V., Trusted Shops GmbH

Role: Workshop SpeakerDate: August 2016

Topics: Accessibility

https://www.aktion-mensch.de/ http://www.trustedshops.de/

Billiger-Mietwagen.de // React Application

· Customer: Billiger-Mietwagen.de, SilverTours GmbH

Role: Front-End ArchitectDate: Jan 2016 - March 2016

Technologies: React.js

https://www.billiger-mietwagen.de/

Vaillant, Saunier Duval Brand Group // Websites

- Customer: Vaillant Group Business Services GmbH
- Role: Front-End Developer
- Date: July 2014 December 2015
- Technologies: "Component based Development", Grunt, Javascript (jQuery), SASS (CSS3), HTML5, Accessibility, Responsive Web Design

http://www.vaillant.de/ http://www.vaillant.com/ http://www.saunierduval.com/

Share A Camper // Website, Portal

- Customer: Share A Camper GmbH
- Role: Front-End Architect & Developer, UX-Designer
- Date: Juni August 2015
- Technologies: Grunt, Browserify, SASS, Material Design, Responsive Design

https://www.shareacamper.com

MPS Public Solutions // Application

Customer: MPS Public Solutions GmbHRole: Front-End Architect, Agile Coach

• Date: Mai - Juli 2015

 Technologies: Coaching, Angular.js, Grunt, SASS, Scrum, Teams Processes & Workflows

http://www.mps-solutions.de/

Aktion Mensch // Accessibility Workshop, Training

· Customer: Aktion Mensch e.V., Kuehlhaus AG

• Role: Workshop Speaker

• Date: Juli 2015

Topics: Accessibility, Website Architecture

https://www.aktion-mensch.de/ http://www.kuehlhaus.com/

Stadt Hamburg // Workshop, Training

Customer: LGV HamburgRole: Workshop Speaker

• Date: April 2015

• Topics: Javascript, Backbone & Require.js, Grunt, SASS, HTML5, Accessibility, Scalability, Application Architecture

http://www.hamburg.de/

.. Ask me if you want to see the years 2009 to 2014.

Work Experience

2016 - present

Freelance Agile Coach & Scrum Master

www.ixis.io

2009 - 2016	Freelance Front-End Developer www.ixis.io
2011 - 2014	Frontend Developer - nexum AG www.nexum.de
2010 - 2012	Freelance Web Developer - Haimspiel Media GmbH www.haimspiel-media.de
2010 - 2011	Freelance Web Developer - Merida2 GmbH www.merida2.de
2010 - 2012	PHP-Developer and Designer - CoreCMS (Open-Source)
2009 - 2011	Application Developer eLearning - German Sport University Cologne www.dshs-koeln.de

Education

2008 - 2011 Study of Physics - University of Cologne (until 2009)

Magisterium

Study of Sports and Performance - German Sport University Cologne
Bachelor of Science
Comprehensive school, Willy-Brandt Cologne Graduation from high school

1994 - 1998 Primary School, PPS Cologne



1998 - 2007

Cologne, last updated 28 September 2017, Andreas Klein